Guide to the Mary Dowdell Ashley Film Collection, 1937-1975 RL.10048
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Films, 1936-1967; 1
  - Reel 7, 1950-1951; 7
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 11. Hull Street, front yard: Big Ann (hat & gloves) & Exie holding clothes basket with Myrick in it; Bonnie with book in hands & Ann; Myrick in clothes basket.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 12. Hull Street, front yard: Bonnie on sled using hose to wash feet.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 13. Perdido, AL?: group in water; water skiing scene.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 14. Oak Mountain State Park, AL: Camp Talahi (Girl Scout Camp): Visitors' day -- Margaret Harris kneeling; Ann, 3 girls (2 in Brownie uniforms) - plaid shirt: Kitty Poyntz?, green cap: Medora Powell, Charlotte Poyntz?; Ginny (tongue out); Bonnie; Ann (blue top); scene at waterfront.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 15. Hull Street, front yard: Easter?: Ginny, Ann, & Bonnie dressed for Sunday School.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 16. Mary Esther, FL: Bonnie in straw hat & orange life preserver; rest of family in small boat with attached motor: Daddy by motor, Ann in orange life preserver, Margaret Harris in blue & pink cap, Ginny in red cap, Wiley Ashley, Jr. Later: Daddy with Myrick as baby on inner tube & Ann to left, Bonnie with yellow/red/blue inflatable horse; Ann swimming; Wiley diving off diving board; Mother holding Myrick with Ann beside in water; Ann jumping off pier; Mother holding Bonnie's & Ann's hands in shallow water beside pier; Ann swimming; Mother in green bathing suit on pier; Ann & Bonnie on pier & then with Daddy; Ginny on diving board - dives in & swims - close-up of Ginny in red bathing suit; Ann swimming; Daddy in motor boat.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 17. Mary Esther, FL: Gulf: Daddy on beach next to Bonnie in inner tube; view of the Gulf.
    Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 18. Montgomery, AL: downtown: Thanksgiving Day parade (annual parade prior to Alabama State University vs. Tuskegee University - both historically Black institutions - football game) along Dexter Avenue: floats, marching band; majorettes; young girls as majorettes; classes of school children in uniforms; float with label: Races United for Defense.
    - Original 16mm film, 1950-1951; 400 film feet (Freezer Smith, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0007)
      MD5: 92da81fe9a9326132a8d3cfcba7e66b8
  - Reel 8, 1936
    Europe 1936 color.
    - Original 16mm film, 1936 (Box 2, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0014)
  - Reel 9, 1937-1938; 9
    Original notes on can: Riomar Club, Florida, winter 1937; Pelham, 1938; Mary Esther, Fall 1938, Montgomery
    Additional description: Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 1. Winter Haven, FL: Cypress Gardens: foliage; backs of Big Ann & grandfather, who turn & walk towards camera; bell tower; more foliage; backs of Big Ann & grandfather at bottom of bell tower or some monument; skinny male ?Uncle Phil Branson? walks up to our grandfather; grandfather in white cap in position to hit golf ball -- hits it & hits another; ? hitting golf ball; Uncle Phil (long legs) hitting golf ball & then grandfather hitting.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 2. Vero Beach, FL: Riomar Club -- beach: 4 men, 1st being our grandfather; in bathing suits with water in background; 2 of men & 3 women lounging on beach; men & women throwing ball on beach; 4 men standing/drinking in wooden structure; grandfather in white hat; close-ups of grandfather & couple of others.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 3. Pelham, NY: mother on left & Little Ann on right; they walk in front of blooming bush/tree & walk around more; close-up of Little Ann in front of ? DARK; playing badminton; mother? in blue shorts; view of yard with blooming trees.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 4. Pelham, NY: snow scene of Monterey Avenue yard; see Little Ann & Mother on & near street.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 5. Pelham, NY: no snow: Little Ann in blue shirt on left & friend on right; 2 women dressed alike in pinkish skirts & black blouses; little girl in black coat; close-up of little boy making a face; close-up of 1 of women, perhaps Little Ann; little girl; flower bushes in background.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 6. Pelham, NY: convertible; little boy in car -- 1 or both of women in previous scene get into car; little girl also in car; adult female, perhaps Big Ann, with hand shading face sitting in chair in yard; back of adult male who plays badminton with another adult male;men walking & then 1 sitting on ground & drinking out of 2 glasses.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 7. Destin, FL: bridge spanning large body of water; boat docks at one end of bridge; views of sand & ocean; someone in white, perhaps Mother, walking at water's edge.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 8. Mary Esther, FL: 2 adults on pier; shore & large white building; house behind trees may be Aunt Mamie & Uncle Phil Branson's; views of water & shore; few people visible.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 9. Montgomery, AL: downtown: celebration at Capitol where people on steps.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 10. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street: back of convertible; man in white apron walks towards camera; porch of Perry Street apartment building: DARK: ? Walks towards camera; see women carrying loads on heads & walking down street.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 11. Location? Little Ann in bridesmaid's dress in front of white building; Little Ann walking around.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 12. Montgomery, AL, near downtown: horse pulling wagon down street; close-up of young black female waling down street; black woman with decorative hat or bundle on head walking down street; street scenes; horse pulling wagon down street.
    Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 13. Location? Little Ann in graduation robe; street scenes; DARK.
    - Original 16mm film, 1937-1938; 375 film feet (Freezer Smith, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0009)
  - Reel 10, 1936; Film is in the advanced stages of acetate decay, could not be digitized, and therefore is not viewable.
    Europe 1936, black and white
    - Original 16mm film, 1936 (Box 2, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0015)
  - Reel 11, 1949; 11
    Original notes on can: 1949 - Tennis - Jack Kramer. Ginny and friend. Ann and Ginny - Cotton Picking Beach. Bonnie / baby. Ann w/Mother. Opelika.
    Additional description: Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 1. Tennis tournament with Jack Kramer vs. ?
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: Helen Cottingham's kindergarten: Ginny in dance recital costume hanging upside down on swing; Ginny jumping rope; Kitty Poyntz, Ginny, ? Mary Lou Stuart, & ?,? ?.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 3. Location?: "? ford": swimming pool: Daddy with Myrick (?) on shoulder; Ginny jumping into water; 3 female friends of Mother & Daddy on side of pool; Ginny swimming; Daddy in inner tube with Ginny in foreground & female friend of Mother & Daddy on porch in background; Myrick (CHECK ON DATE; VALID FOR Myrick TO BE IN SCENE??)standing on side of pool; Mother holding ball in pool with ? Ginny on side; Daddy, Ginny & Myrick on inner tube.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 4. Ginny & Ann, & then with Dear in background & then Little Ann at left.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 5. Mt. Meigs, near Montgomery, AL: Cotton picking: regular cotton pickers; soon Exie in blue skirt & white shirt, more regular pickers, then Ann & Ginny & maybe Bonnie with Exie; weighing bales of cotton, after which cotton was emptied into a truck.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 6. Mary Esther, FL: Walking across Santa Rosa Island from sound to the Gulf: male friend of Mother & Daddy in red trunks Ginny with pigtails in white suit; Ann with yellow inner tube around neck; Daddy, tall female (?), Bill Thetford, Ginny & ? Margaret Harris; in water: Bill Thetford & Ginny swimming; Ann (in trunks) & ? Margaret Harris in 2-piece suit.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 7. Mary Esther, FL: Santa Rosa Sound in front of house renting: Ann sitting in water; Two plus Ginny on pier & then swimming; ?Margaret Harris on pier; Ann in inner tube; Bill Thetford & ?; Bonnie as baby.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 8. Mary Esther, FL?: Gulf: Daddy; ? in inner tubes; Ginny on back in water; ???? Swimming.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 9. Mary Esther, FL: Santa Rosa Sound: group in water -- two swimming forward with Ginny on right; Ann in water, then holding ball & ?; Mother in 2-piece suit walking behind Ann, then holding beach ball; group in water; Ann in yellow inner tube;?oOn left & Ann on right; man in red trunks with child on other side; Ginny & Ann with yellow inner tube; Ginny splashing Ann; child in foreground with Ann behind with yellow inner tube; group in water with pier in background; Mother in 2-piece suit; Mother with Ann in yellow inner tube, then Ginny on right.
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 10. Hull Street?: Bonnie, Ginny with corsage, ?, Ann in Sunday dress
    Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 11. Opelika, AL: Home of Aunt Annie & Aunt Jeanette: front porch steps: back row: Aunt Virginia (Gin) with hands on face, Aunt Jeanette, Aunt Minnie, Aunt Annie; next row: Aunt Lettie in black & Big Ann holding Bonnie & Ginny standing in front of Daddy & Ann with back to camera. Back yard: Bonnie on stomach on quilt on ground; Ann, close-up; chairs: Aunt Minnie with Aunt Virginia (Gin)on left, Aunt Annie leaning over Ann & Bonnie on quilt.
    - Original 16mm film, 1949; 350 film feet (Box 1, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0011)
  - Reel 12 and 13, 1950; 12
    Original notes on can: 12: Mary Esther - Ann and Bonnie w/half her hair. Ginny; 13: Katty w/crab - 1950. Ginny in boat - Hull St. Ginny, Ann and Bonnie. Margaret Day - Birthday Party. Joy, Louise, Ann, Ginny on horses, Easter Hunt. Bonnie walking. Fishing.
    Additional description: Reel 12. Sequence 68. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: Ginny (blue & white striped shirt), Ann, & Bonnie (baby) in hammock in front of house family renting; Santa Rosa Sound in front of house - small boat in which family went across sound, then left boat at pier & walked across Santa Rosa Island to the Gulf; Bonnie (right) & Ann (left) in straw hats in boat & Ginny in back - ? on beach; Mother in red hat holding Myrick; Uncle Eddie Stauss & Uncle Phil Branson?; Daddy sitting on edge of boat which is to right of a similar boat; ? comes towards boat; Ann? in red inner tube; little boy - Hank Hutchinson? in blue in inner tube in water; 2 people catching crab; Ginny's back (in bathing suit with blue back & design on white background in front).
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL (cont'd): Pier & boat (possibly Uncle Phil's), probably in front of Aunt Mamie & Uncle Phil's house: Bill? Thetford in mostly blue shirt; Ginny in plaid shirt; Mother in blue checked shirt & male leaning on boat; Bill? Thetford dove & Ginny jumped off pier & swam; both get on pier; on beach, Mother & Bonnie (baby); close-up of Ann & then Bonnie with almost no hair on left side of head (note: Bonnie went through stage of pulling out her hair on left side, probably when taking naps -- eventually overcame this practice); Bonnie playing in sand & in shallow water; Daddy sitting on edge of small boat; Bonnie & Ann standing in blue bathing suits; view of Santa Rosa Sound, pier & house -- Ann & Bonnie sitting on steps. 13* on original list, but contents of reel 13 are on reel 12.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Union Springs, AL: Pond: Small boat with Emily Hobbie (?) in back & Ginny, each with an oar; Jack & Emily Hobbie (parents of Emily) standing beside Daddy (hat on); parents of Emily in boat with Emily in front & Ginny in back.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. Hull Street, front yard: Ginny pushing Bonnie (pink snowsuit) in "taylor tot" along gravel path; Ann in navy appears.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 4. Hull Street, back yard: Ann (blue dress) & Bonnie on some small rocking horse contraption & Margaret Day in white dress & pink sweater; other children at birthday party for Ann & Bonnie; Ann guarding gifts on decorated table; view of back of house showing upstairs porch & broad rectangular columns under porch, that is, back of first floor. Different day: Bonnie on rocking horse & Louise Clark in blue dress (white stripe on front top center of dress); side wall of fire station (brick painted white) which was at end of back yard: Ann in blue dress watering hollyhocks; back of house: Daddy brings watering can with water to Ann; Big Ann in back behind Bonnie in taylor tot.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 5. Location?: Libby Foster (?), Lila Ashley, older girl (?), Ginny on fence, Wiley Ashley, Jr. on horse; Louise Clark, then Joy Clark on horse; then Ginny climbing onto horse; then Ann with Lila Ashley behind her on horse.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 6. Hull Street, front yard: Easter egg hunt; several small children; Sarah Lingham in white dress with yellow ribbon & Ginny in blue dress, each holding basket of Easter eggs; DARK: Ann?; Ginny in jeans & shirt holding basket of Easter eggs. DARK: hunting Easter eggs -- family wearing jeans. Later in day: Ann & Ginny dressed for Sunday School, probably Easter; Ann in blue dress & straw hat; on gravel path in front of banana shrub: Ginny, Bonnie, male, female, Louise & Joy Clark -- most holding Easter baskets; all hunting eggs; close-up of Ann in blue smocked dress. At a later time: Bonnie standing up from small chair (had been grandfather Dowdell's), walks a few steps & then crawls.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 7. Location? Pond: Mother & Daddy's friends.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 8. Location? Beach: children swimming; adults & Ginny in blue bathing suit with back to camera; ? With her; view of beach & water.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Sarajevo?: leg braces, etc. on ground -- memorial??; filmed in black & white.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: John & Algie Neill's back yard with swimming pool: swimming lessons being taught.
    Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. commercial film in black & white: Castle Films presents Merry Christmas; titles before each scene; c. MCML, United World Films.
    - Original 16mm film, 1950; 300 film feet (Freezer Smith, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0012)
  - Reel 14, 1947; 8
    Original notes on can: 1947 - Ginny - Beach - Spout - Ginny Birthday Party. Baby Ann - Snow, Ann and Ginny on sled. Edgar Stuart and boat - Gulf w/Big Ann
    Additional description: Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 1. Location?: Beach (?): Ginny in trunks in water; then in inner tube; little boy (?) in inner tube; female (?) in 2-piece white bathing suit wading; Daddy in water; Mother in 2-piece blue bathing suit & bandage on knee; Mother holding Ginny's hand; little boy, his mother (white bathing suit with black design) & his father.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 2. Location?: Beach (?), new scene: close-up of Daddy on boat, couple mentioned in previous scene; Barnett Wood (?) in foreground; close-up of Mother in white top; close up of male (?); close-up of Mother; previous male & another male.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 3. Location?: Ginny dressed up in white dress & pantaloons & bonnet for birthday.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 4. Coosa, AL: spout: back of Ginny next to back of Aunt Virginia; then DARK; see spout, made of wood: back of Aunt Annie or Aunt Jeanette on left & ? on right; few people at end of spout where water spilling; Mother in 2-piece bathing suit; Daddy with Ginny; Ginny & Daddy standing with Mother sitting; Daddy & Ginny walk around & then sit down.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 5. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street -- 600 block, back-yard of Hobbie family (1/2 block from 640 South Perry Street where Big Ann & Ashley family lived): Ginny's 5th birthday party: large round table decorated with balloons; Exie with Ann in lap sitting in swing; Ginny in white pinafore rolls baby carriage to them & beyond; Ginny taking gift from child in bonnet with ? next to her & holding a little boy's hand; another boy (blonde hair) at left of screen; another part of yard: female in plaid dress in center with children on both sides; front left: ? in white dress; on right Margaret Harris (?) in white dress; back of little boy, probably Bill Thetford; children behind playing "pin the tail on the donkey.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 5. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street (cont'd): back to table with birthday cake (5 lighted candles), showing Ginny blowing them out; children & adults around table; children being served pieces of birthday cake; Ginny opening presents: Joy Clark (?) with pigtails next to her & other children around; Melissa Folsom (?) with dark hair parted in middle, turns towards camera; more of Ginny opening gifts; Sammy Baker (?) holding handle of wagon stacked with gifts, & Bill Thetford next to him; ? in front & Ginny to side by wagon; Sammy pulls wagon with gifts falling off & children picking them up.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 6. Location? Ann on back drinking bottle of orange juice or milk in crib.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 7. Location?: Beach (?): Daddy sitting in water & holding Ann with Ginny in inner tube beside them; Ginny swimming; Exie holding Ann & standing in water; Ginny jumping from edge of boat with Daddy in boat; on left is Big Ann, in center, Uncle Eddie holding a beach ball, & on right, Little Ann in inner tube; Ginny swims towards them; ball throwing; Daddy into water; close-up of Aunt Virginia (black bathing cap) in inner tube; several in water throwing a ball.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 8. Perry Street: Ginny on left; 2 males about the same age building a snow man; Ginny on sled in front with one of males behind her; another into picture; 2 on sled with 2 pulling; sledding & playing in snow; car drives up & parks behind another car on side street perpendicular to Perry; snowball throwing; apartment building in background; adult female at left; can see snow covered old Ford owned by Big Ann; another adult on right; more sledding
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene. Perry Street (cont'd) - may be next day: very sunny; Daddy pulling sled, with Ann in front of Ginny, around front yard; corner with Mother behind Ginny & Ann on sled & going downhill; Mother pulling sled with Ann & Ginny up the hill; front yard with Daddy pulling Ann & Ginny on sled; Exie in background, also apartment building; Mother on left and then center with sled; Mother behind Ginny & Ann on sled; also see Exie & Daddy.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 9. Perry Street, front of apartment: Ann in taylor tot with Adelaide Ashley holding handle; Ginny in red coat on left; opening present - ? Ann's birthday?; Louise Clark in yellow coat & Joy Clark (long blond hair) in red coat standing next to Adelaide; all 5 in view.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 10. Location? Beach: Edgar Stuart in motor boat; Little Ann sitting on seat in boat; then 2 adult males & Edgar Stuart in boat waving; on pier, Boots Ashley (Sharman) in multi-colored shirt walking up steps from beach; Daddy carrying inner tube with Ginny in front of him & ? in front of her.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 11. Location? Gulf: Mother in 2 piece bathing suit; Daddy standing; Ginny or ? In water in inner tube; waves & sand; close-up of Daddy on left; Wiley Ashley, Jr. ? & Ginny with long hair; Big Ann in black bathing suit; all playing in water; Ginny swimming Big Ann, Ginny, Wiley, Jr. & Mother in 2 piece bathing suit all playing in waves.
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 12. Location? Picnic on towel; baby in center is Ann & Ginny on right; ? On left in pigtails & 2 boys?; birthday cake with 6 candles on towel -- Ginny's birthday?
    Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 13. Location? Children in water with some in inner tubes; beach & trees in one area; Mother in water in 2 piece bathing suit.
    - Original 16mm film, 1947; 425 film feet (Box 1, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0008)
  - Reel 15, 1942-1944
    Ginny - baby, Florida, Winter Park, Daytona, 1942, 43-44, Clearwater
    - Original 16mm film, 1942-1944; 400 film feet (Box 2, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0016)
  - Reel 16, 1945; 10
    Original notes on can: Pelham 1945 - Pea Island - Ginny on Beach and ice skaing - Birthday Party - Fishing Ginny on horse - Coast - Ann (baby).
    Additional description: Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 1. Pea Island, NY: Ginny's birthday -- Ginny behind cake; group of children sitting on ground & tablecloth with plates, etc. on it; group of adult women standing & 1 man to far right; Ginny with bangs & in swim trunks; little girl beside her; adults sitting nearer camera & 1 male adult standing to right; little boy flying kite with Ginny beside him; Ginny & little girl playing in sand; Ginny runs into water & then she & little girl both run into water where there are others; sailboat & another boat in background; view of water & part of shore.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 2. Pelham, NY: Ginny in snowsuit on ice; skates on ice.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene. Pelham, NY -- warmer time of year: Ginny in white blouse & blue skirt beside wall; Ginny running; Ginny with adult female, probably Little Ann.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 3. Pelham, NY: Ginny in snowsuit going down steps in front of Monterey Avenue house; Ginny in snowsuit in snow.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 4. Location? Ginny's birthday party; table with gifts; Dear in pillbox hat; close-up of Scott Hereford; girls in background; Ginny in yellow dress opening gifts.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 5. Location? Pond: Boat with male on left; Ginny standing in center & Daddy on right; Mills Thornton Sr. on left; Daddy gets fishing pole ready for Ginny to fish; another boat (red) with Ginny & Mills Thornton Jr.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 6. Location? Ginny being put on horse; someone leads the horse around; Wiley Ashley Jr. in white shorts & shirt on right; Ginny off horse & Wiley on horse & is led around; long wagon with Ginny, Wiley & other children being pulled by horse; Wiley on horse again.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene. Location? (cont'd) 4 children: far right -- Ginny in pinafore & saddle oxfords; Mary Kennan Thetford in white pinafore next to her; on left, ?Bill & Bob Thetford? In white shirts with blue collars & blue shorts; Wiley Ashley Jr. appears; Ginny, Mary Kennan, Bill & Bob; Ginny on horse again being led around.
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 7. Mary Esther, FL: Daddy on far right in inner tube & then female adult in white bathing cap & Ginny on left paddling; male adult on left in inner tube; little boy & probably his mother; mother in white 2 piece bathing suit with Ginny in front; on right same adult male in inner tube & little boy; Ginny splashing/paddling again; Mother does back stroke; front of cottage (not visible) where staying -- gate with view of ? (Ginny's handwriting not legible).
    Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene. Mary Esther, FL (cont'd): Ginny in overalls & hat; bench on pier -- adult male's back, little boy or girl in pink cap & Ginny? in straw hat & horizontal striped t shirt; front view of 3 on bench (Ginny standing); female servant in all white & white hat fishing beside the 3; to her right, Daddy fishing; Ann in white on striped beach towel being propped up by ? & then on her stomach; Ann being held.
    - Original 16mm film, 1945; 300 film feet (Box 1, Film-reel RL10048-F16-0010)
  - Reel 17, 1950; 13
    Original notes on can: Sarajevo; Castle Films presents a Yuletide Movie, "Merry Christmas"